# MIRZA SUMAIYA ALAM

# Frontend Developer

#### **PROFILE**

Creative, meticulous, and certified web developer with 2 years of frontend experience who is passionate about learning new technologies. Capable of writing well-structured code, offering smooth and wise solutions to the problems that arise, adapting at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment, and determining customer satisfaction.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer / ChargePanel AB / Stockholm / June 2022 – December 2022

- Created UX wireframe of Direct Payment web App from specification.
- Developed Direct Payment Web App (Frontend) using Preact, TypeScript, GraphQL.
- Involved in Developing multiple React Native Apps from same code base using React Native, XCode, Android studio, GraphQL.
- Created new Apps for new clients from existing white label ChargePanel App.
- Involved in redesigning UX/UI of ChargePanel App and Enterprise System.

Junior Developer / GuidePal / Stockholm / Aug 2021 – March 2022

- Developing Travel and City Guide App for Android and iOS using React-Native, GraphQL, MongoDB.
- Unit testing using JEST and UI testing using Cavy.
- Involved in developing GuidePal official website using ReactJS.
- Involved in Integrating in-app-purchase for Android and iOS
- Involved in Integrating Stripe payment method.

Front-end Developer Intern (LIA2) / VivoLogica / Stockholm / Dec 2020 - Feb 2021

- Implemented a system for medical researchers using ReactJS.
- Implemented QR code scanner and reader. Read and handle JSON information after scanning.

Front-end Developer Intern (LIA1) / Semsomi / Stockholm / Mar 2020 - May 2020

Worked in an auto-generated news app for android system using React-Native.

Full Stack Developer (Trainee) / </SALT> / Stockholm / Aug 2018 - Oct 2018

 Developed projects in Test Driven Development(TDD) using JavaScript, NodeJS, REST, Express, Middleware.

Network Engineer / Sheba Phone / Dhaka, Bangladesh / Dec 2007 - Apr 2010

Monitoring, troubleshooting and configuring Soft Switch, BSS, Media Gateway, OMC server.

# **EDUCATION**

- Yrkes Utbildning in Frontend Developer / EC Utbildning / 2019 2021
- Master's in Information Systems Management / Stockholm University / 2011 2015
- Master's in Interactive Media Design / Södertörns Högskola / 2010 2011
- B.Sc in Computer Engineering / American International University-Bangladesh / 2002
   2006



## **CONTACT**

Email: shorna\_159@yahoo.com Phpne: +46(0)707172287

LinkedIn:

www.linkedin.com/in/mirzasumaiyaalam/ GitHub: https://github.com/MSumaiya

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

UX/UI **HTML** CSS **JavaScript** React **React Native** TypeScript GraphQL **XCode** Angular Cavy SQL TDD **Figma JEST Firebase** Agile Docker **Kubernetes NodeJS** MongoDB

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

English (Fluent)
Swedish (Basic/Completed SFI-D)
Bengali (Native).

#### REFERENCES

Available on request